(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T21:16:51.745804",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
HAPPY MUSIC
[Song: HAPPY MUSIC]
どうかしてる　また同じシャツを
What's wrong with me? Searching for...
いないはずの　人込みに探してた
...that same shirt in the crowd where you shouldn't be.
だれといても　何を話しても
No matter who I'm with or what we talk about...
映るすべて　やだ　また　かさねている
...everything I see, oh no, I'm overlapping with you again.
名前しか知らない　なのにね　こんなに
I only know your name, and yet...
気になるの……これって　もしかして
...why do I care this much? Could this be...?
ほら　たった今　あたしのなかで　響くよ　ハッピーミュージック
Look, right now, Happy Music is echoing inside of me!
運命の針を胸に落として　奏でる
Dropping the needle of fate onto my heart, playing music.
大事な日も　まじめな時も　手加減なしの　パワープレイ
On important days or serious times, an unsparing power play!
誰よりも先　あなたを見つけたくて
Wanting to find you before anyone else...
ダーリン　今度も　あのシャツきてきて
Darling, wear that shirt next time too!
こんぬい！ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアでーす！
Kon-nui! I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen!
この度は不知火フレア2024 BEMANI楽曲3Dライブ 始まりましたー！
Welcome! The Shiranui Flare 2024 BEMANI Songs 3D Live has begun!
1曲目 Happy Music ゲームサイズでお届けさせていただきましたが どうでしたか？
We kicked things off with "Happy Music" in its game size format! How did you like it?
今回この衣装は ポエットちゃんに寄せてみて 天使っぽい感じにさせていただきました
For this outfit, I styled it after Poet-chan to give it a bit of an angelic feel!
Happy Music 大好きな楽曲なので今回歌わせていただきました！
I love "Happy Music" so much, so I'm really happy I got to sing it today!
今回はタイトルにもあるように BEMANI楽曲ライブとなっております！
As you can see in the title, today's live is dedicated to BEMANI songs!
BEMANI楽曲で構成させていただきました！
The entire setlist is made of BEMANI songs!
KONAMIさんにこんな熱い気持ちを一方的にお伝えさせていただいたら 全面的にご協力してくださいまして...
After I passionately expressed my love for BEMANI to KONAMI, they were kind enough to fully support us!
なんとですね 見てください！ステージすごいんですよ！
And guess what? Look at this! Ta-da! Today's stage is amazing!
KONAMIさんから素材をお借りさせていただきまして ご用意していただいたりとかしまして...
KONAMI provided us with all these official graphics and assets for the stage!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い... フレアがポップン派なので 大体ポップンなんですけど...
It's so cute! Since Flare is a big Pop'n Music fan, most of it is Pop'n-themed, but...
DDRとか 下のキーボードはノスタルジアなのかな？ KEYBOARDMANIAなのかな？ どっちなんだい！みたいな
There's DDR, and the keyboard down here... is it Nostalgia? Or KeyboardMania? Which one could it be?!
こんな感じで SOUND VOLTEX みたいな感じで...
There are so many details, like Sound Voltex up to here...
BEMANI要素を詰め詰めにしたステージになりました！本当にありがとうございます！
We made a stage packed full of BEMANI elements! Thank you so much!
ご協力いただきました ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all your support!
完全にもうフレアのやりたい放題みたいなライブになっておりますので...
This live has really become a dream come true for Flare, where I get to do whatever I want...
これが結果的にとっても嬉しいお知らせに繋がるかもしれない... 繋がらないかもしれない... お楽しみにということで！
This might lead to some super exciting news in the future... or maybe not! Look forward to finding out!
ハッシュタグは #不知火フレア生誕祭2024 でございます！
The hashtag for today is #ShiranuiFlareBirthday2024!
こちらでスクショとかポストとか色々してもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd be super happy if you could share screenshots and post using the hashtag!
この後どんな曲が出てくるのかは 完全にフレアの好みと独断と偏見で選んでいるので...
As for what songs are coming up next, they were chosen entirely based on my personal favorites and bias!
皆さん楽しみにしながら待ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
So I hope you'll all stay tuned and enjoy the show!
知らない方も「あ、こんな曲があるんだ！」と知ってもらえたら嬉しいなと思います！
Even if you don't know the songs, I'd be happy if you discover new songs you like!
明日にはポップンしに行こうとか SOUND VOLTEXしに行こうとか思ってもらえたら嬉しいなと思うので...
It'd be awesome if this makes you want to go play Pop'n or Sound Voltex tomorrow!
楽しみにしていてください！
Please look forward to the rest of the show!
最後まで見てくれないと泣いちゃうかも... しくしく、えーんえーん、チラ... えーんえーん、泣いちゃうかも！
If you don't watch until the end, I might cry... Sob sob, waaaah... peek... waaaah! I'm gonna cry!
ナ・カ・ナ・イ・デ
Don't cry
本当の孤独も知らない
You don't even know true loneliness
まだ淡い花びらに
Still on the pale petals
涙の粒 抱えたまま...
Holding onto teardrops...
ah さわらないで
Ah, don't touch me
暖かなその手は
With those warm hands
わたしのすべて狂わす
You drive everything about me mad
ne 許さないで
Hey, don't forgive me
傷口を押さえて
Pressing down on my wound
微笑んでる あなたがいる
There you are, smiling
もう 帰れないね
I can't go back now
堕ちてく時の甘い香り
The sweet scent of falling through time
繰り返すたびにひどくなる
It gets worse every time it repeats
ダ・キ・シ・メ・テ
Hold me close
いまだけ好きだったフリして
Just for now, pretend you loved me
たったひとつだけなら
If it's only just one thing
ぜんぶ ぜんぶ いらない
I don't need anything, anything at all
ナ・カ・ナ・イ・デ
Don't cry
本当の孤独も知らない
You don't even know true loneliness
まだ淡い花びらに
Still on the pale petals
涙の粒 抱えたまま...
Holding onto teardrops...
ah 急がないで
Ah, don't rush
真実なんか ほら
Look, something like the truth
どこにも落ちてないでしょ
Isn't scattered anywhere, is it?
ne 見つめないで
Hey, don't gaze at me
やさしいまなざしを
With those gentle eyes
恨んでいる？ 求めている？
Are you resenting me? Seeking me?
もう わからなくて
I don't even know anymore
キスするときの わたしの顔
My face when we kiss
キスするときの あたしの顔
My face when I kiss you,
もっときれいに 見せたいだけ
I just want to show you an even prettier side of me.
ダ・キ・シ・メ・テ
Hold me tight.
いつでも かわいいフリして
Always pretending to be cute,
真っ赤に色づく日を ずっと ずっと待ってる
I've been waiting and waiting for the day I turn deep red.
ナ・カ・ナ・イ・デ
Please don't cry.
本当の自分も知らずに
Without even knowing my true self,
まだ淡い 花びらに
upon these still-pale petals,
夢の重さ 抱えたまま
while carrying the weight of my dreams...
堕ちてく時の 甘い香り
The sweet scent as I fall
繰り返すたびにひどくなる
gets stronger every time it repeats.
ダ・キ・シ・メ・テ
Hold me tight.
いまだけ 好きだったフリして
Just for now, pretend that you loved me.
たった ひとつだけなら
If it's just that one thing,
ぜんぶ ぜんぶいらない
I don't need anything, anything else.
Bloomin' like a Rose
本当の孤独も知らない
Without even knowing true loneliness,
まだ淡い 花びらに
upon these still-pale petals,
涙の粒 抱えたまま
while holding on to drops of tears...
あともう3センチ
Just 3 centimeters left,
キミのくちびるまで
until I reach your lips.
妄想つなぐ
Connecting my delusions,
イカした夢はなぜか
why is it that these cool dreams
これからってトコでいつも覚める
always wake me up just when things are getting good?
わずかに10センチ
A mere 10 centimeters away,
伸ばす腕ムナしく
my reaching arms stretch out in vain.
閉まる扉
The closing doors,
ホームに独りキミと
alone on the platform with you...
ガラス越しに目と目が合う
through the glass, our eyes meet.
ここハひとつ笑うしかない
Right now, all I can do is laugh.
白線のうしろ立ちあがんだ
I stand back behind the white line.
不覚にも涙がこぼれても
Even if tears unexpectedly fall,
ここハひとつ笑うしかない
right now, all I can do is laugh.
いつかキミまで追いつくかな
I wonder if I'll catch up to you someday.
脱いで捨てちゃうほど
Enough to just take off and throw away,
かわりはいるぞなんて
saying "there's plenty of replacements"...
NO! これどうなの?
NO! What's up with that?
おじいちゃん おばあちゃん
Grandpa, Grandma,
すぐに投げちゃいけないんだよね
you shouldn't just throw things away so quickly, right?
今も昔もこれからずっと
Past, present, and forever into the future,
かわりの僕はどこにもいない
there is no replacement for me anywhere!
もうここハひとつ笑うしかない
Now, all I can do is laugh.
わかり合えるその日が来るまで
Until the day comes when we can truly understand each other.
いつか キミまで 追いつくかな
I wonder if I'll catch up to you someday.
ふたりの 距離は 縮まるかな
Will the distance between us ever shrink?
ノドの 乾きも 忘れたまま
Completely forgetting how dry my throat is...
終わらないよ Chase!
It's not over yet, Chase!
キミの代わりはひとりもいない
There's no one who could ever replace you.
キミの代わりじゃボクはいらない
If it's a replacement for you, I don't want it.
不覚にも涙がこぼれても
Even if tears unexpectedly spill,
もう ここはひとつ 笑うしかない
now there's nothing to do but smile.
今も昔も これからずっと
Past, present, and forever into the future,
かぶりの僕は どこにもいない
there is no duplicate of me anywhere.
ああ そうだったのかって きっと きっと
Ah, thinking, "So that's how it was," surely, surely...
わかりあえる その日が来るから
the day when we truly understand each other will come.
Chase! 今日もひとつ笑うしかない
Chase! Today again, all we can do is smile.
闇に放り込んだ
Cast out into the darkness...
想い 届いていますか？
Are my feelings reaching you?
浅い夢の覚め際に毎日
Every day as I awaken from a shallow dream,
伝う涙の理由はどこから
where do the reasons for these trailing tears come from?
きっと戻ってくるよと 頬を撫でる手は冷たくて
Saying "I'll surely return," the hand stroking my cheek was cold,
ぎゅっと広い背中を抱きしめた
and I tightly embraced your broad back.
謳え 謳え 通い路恋歌 たとえ声はしなくとも
Sing, sing, love song of the path between us, even if my voice won't come out.
届け 届け 通い路恋歌 愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
Reach, reach, love song of the path between us, for the one I love, I'll keep smiling forever.
淡い日々の思い出に毎日
Every day in the memories of faint days,
すがる二人の姿は儚げ
the two of us clinging to each other look so fleeting.
ぐっと押さえ続けた 瞳の奥のやさしさが
The gentleness deep in your eyes that you kept holding back
ふっと返り咲く刹那に溢れる
overflows in the instant it suddenly blooms again.
止まれ 止まれ 防人恋歌 たとえ声はしなくとも
Stop, stop, Sakimori love song, even if there is no voice.
届け 届け 通い路恋歌 愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
Reach, reach, love song of the path between us, for the one I love, I'll keep smiling forever.
貴方の為 君の為 また出会う日までの約束
For your sake, for you, a promise until the day we meet again.
どんな思いが馳せようと 笑顔で居よう
No matter what thoughts run through my mind, let's keep smiling.
遠く 遠く 分かれても
Even if we are separated far, far away,
辛い時は 歌に乗せて…
when times are hard, put it into song...
ずっと待っているよと しがみつく手は震えて
Saying "I'll wait for you forever," the clinging hand trembles,
もっと強く深く深く抱きしめた
and I embraced you even tighter, deeper, deeper.
謳え 謳え 通い路恋歌 たとえ声が枯れても
Sing, sing, love song of the path between us, even if my voice goes hoarse.
笑え 笑え 通い路恋歌 暖かい陽はまどか
Smile, smile, love song of the path between us, the warm sun shines gently.
ずっとずっと謳えるのは 君の声がするから
The reason I can keep singing forever and ever is because I hear your voice.
届け 届け 防人恋歌 愛する人の為 ずっと笑顔で居るから
Reach, reach, Sakimori love song, for the one I love, I'll keep smiling forever.
はい！
All right!
皆さん 見てますかー？
Everyone, are you watching?
はい ということでですね アキちゃんとは「PINK ROSE」を
All right! So then, with Aki-chan we performed "PINK ROSE"...
です！そして...
...and also...
咲煙煙火をソロで歌わせていただきましたー！
I got to sing "Sakimuri Renka" as a solo!
はい。ま、ちょっとね、どうしてこの曲を選んだか
Yes. Well, as for why I chose this song...
みたいなのはね、ま、ちょっとあの...
and all, well...
世代じゃないんですけど
it's not really from my generation, but...
なんかこの好きな曲とか、なんか合いそうな曲、あとは...
like songs I like, or songs that seem to suit me, and also...
ま、みんながね、慣れ親しんだポップンと言えば、みたいな曲だったり
songs that everyone is familiar with when thinking of Pop'n Music...
ま、Pink Roseはキーボードマニアの曲なんですけど...
Well, "Pink Rose" is a Keyboardmania song, though...
ま、でもみんな好きな曲をちょっと選曲したら、選曲差はバラバラなのでね
Well, since I picked songs that everyone likes, the selection ended up being pretty varied.
とか、咲煙煙火は、もう思い出があったらヤバい...
And as for "Sakimuri Renka", if you have memories with it, that's crazy...
ヤバいんですけど、
it's crazy, but...
あの、好きな曲だったのでちょっとチョイスさせていただきました！いや、本当でも難しかったです。
it's a song I loved, so I chose it! But wow, it was really difficult.
でもですね、今日はですね、衣装変わりましてけれども、
Anyway, today my outfit changed, but...
今日はなんとですね、私の希望で
today, thanks to my own request...
今回ポップンミュージック High Cheer! が遊べると聞いたんですけど...
I heard that I can play Pop'n Music High Cheer! this time...
え？どこに...どこにあるんでしょう？ちょっと探してみましょうか。
Huh? Where... where could it be? Let's go look for it.
どこどこどこどこ どこどこどこどこ どこどこ...
Where, where, where... Where is it?
あ！
Ah!
これー！やったー！
It's this! Yay!
大好き！
I love it!
えー、すごいよ！この技術はすごい技術ですよ！
Woah, this is amazing! This technology is incredible!
皆さん、なかなかVTuberが実機で遊んでいるところを見る機会がないと思うんですけど...
Everyone, I think you rarely get a chance to see a VTuber playing on a real arcade cabinet...
いや、本当にコナミさん、運営さん、本当にありがとうございます！
Seriously, thank you so much to Konami and the management team!
今回はこちらの可愛い筐体で遊ばせていただくんですけど、
This time I get to play on this cute cabinet,
皆さん、このステージ気付きましたか？こちらですね、なんとスピーカー...このスピーカーとかですね、
did everyone notice this stage? Right here, there are speakers... like these speakers...
ステージ側にもあるんですけれど、
they're also over on the stage side as well,
こちらね、合わせていただいたりとかして、コナミさんがね、ステージ素材をご用意してくださったんですよ！
they matched them for this! Konami actually provided the stage assets for us!
いや、本当にもう本当にありがとうございます！
Seriously, thank you so, so much!
なんかコナミさんにおんぶに抱っこで、本当にすみません！
I feel like I'm relying on Konami for everything, I'm so sorry!
私の今日やりたいことをたくさんお願いして、ダメ元でお願いしたら、たくさん応えてくださって本当ありがとうございます！
I requested so many things I wanted to do today, thinking "it doesn't hurt to ask", and they answered so many of them! Thank you so much!
頭が上がりませんが、せっかくなんでね、早速ちょっと遊ばせていただこうかなと思います！
I can't thank them enough, but since I have the chance, I'd like to jump right into playing!
じゃあ、ちょっと...いいですか？
Alright then... shall we?
とりあえず「Happy Birthday」のところ叩かせていただいてね、
First, let me tap the "Happy Birthday" area...
ポンポンポン...ってこれ、画面にクラッカーが映ったりとかするんですけど、
Tap tap tap... see, crackers pop up on the screen and stuff,
今回は...
this time...
自分のマイカードで遊ばせていただけるということで！
I can play using my own e-amusement card!
ちょっと暗証番号は見せられないんで、ちょっと待ってくださいね！
I can't show my PIN code, so hold on a sec!
はい！
Alright!
こうしてチョチョイのチョイと入れさせていただきましたよ！
And just like that, I typed it right in!
うわあ！ポップンミュージックだ！
Whoa! It's Pop'n Music!
いつも遊ばせていただいております！お世話になっております！ありがとうございます！
I play this all the time! Thank you as always for everything!
ということでですね、今日は推しを使わせていただきます。ちょっとね、今回は...
So today, I'm going to use my favorite character. This time...
あの、ボーカルライブということで、ボーカル縛りで3曲をね、
since this is a vocal live, I wanted to pick 3 songs with a vocal theme,
選ばせていただこうと思ったんですけど、
so I decided to choose those,
今日のラインナップ、3曲は...
today's lineup of 3 songs...
ポップンミュージックで一番好きな曲、「oto」でまず遊ばせていただこうかと思います！
First off, I'm going to play my absolute favorite Pop'n Music song, "oto"!
もう、大好きなぶんですよね〜！
Because I just love it so much!
でもまあ、ちょっとHYPERで許していただきたいと思います！
Though please forgive me, I'll be playing on HYPER mode!
今日選ぶ3曲の中で、個人的には一番難しい！難しいです！
Out of the 3 songs I chose today, this one is personally the hardest for me! It's hard!
難しかったんですけど、一番大好きな曲なので選ばせていただきました！
It was hard, but it's my favorite song so I had to pick it!
ボーカルでこの曲選んでいいのかって話なんですけど
Whether it's right to pick this song for a vocal section is another story, though!
この静かに始まる感じとね...
This quiet beginning and...
最後に来る縦連とかが難しいんですよね〜
the vertical spams near the end are really tough, you know?
これ、配信バフでフルコンとかできないかな？無理か！
I wonder if I can get a Full Combo with stream luck? Probably impossible!
ちょっと音ゲーマー...コンボ繋がってる時だけは喋れないと言おうと思ったんですけど、切れちゃいましたね！
I was gonna say rhythm gamers can't talk while keeping a combo, but I broke it!
右手にも推し、左手にも推し。幸せですね〜！
My fave on my right hand, my fave on my left hand. So happy~
あー！縦連が苦手なんです！許してください！
Ah! I'm so bad at vertical spams! Forgive me!
ライナワショーイ
Raina Washoey!
神曲も...
Such a god-tier song...
歌いたかったですね
I really wanted to sing it.
また何かしら機会があったら歌わせてください
If there's another opportunity, please let me sing it!
どうして後半がグズグズになってしまう...
Why does the second half get so sloppy...
あー！神曲！
Ah! What a god-tier song!
ここがきつ...
This part is tough...
あー、なんとか取れたかな？大丈夫かな？
Ah, did I manage to pull it off? Is it okay?
あー、フレアが一番好きな曲です
Ah, this is Flare's absolute favorite song.
やっぱり「おと」と読みます
As expected, it's read as "Oto".
あー、大好き
Ah, I love it!
あ、推しです。推しのMZDさんです、これどちらも
Ah, he's my fave. MZD is my fave, both of these!
今日はですね、選ぶ3曲のうちの2曲がちょっとMZDの曲なんですけど
Today, 2 out of the 3 songs I chose are MZD songs,
どうしてもみんなでやりたかったやつもあった... それ最後にしたいなと思ったんで、ちょっとMZDで挟んじゃうんですけど
but there's one I really wanted to do with everyone... I wanted to do that last, so MZD songs are sandwiching it.
今回ちょっとライブでは歌わないのですが
I won't be singing this one during the live, but...
やはりね、ポップンと言えばの中で、結構「凛として咲く花の如く」じゃないかっていう方も、たくさんいらっしゃったので
When you think of Pop'n, a lot of people were saying "Nadeshiko Rock" ("Rin to shite Saku Hana no Gotoku"),
ちょっと「凛として咲く花の如く」を叩かせていただこうかと思います
so I'm going to play "Rin to shite Saku Hana no Gotoku"!
よろしくお願いします！
Here we go!
ちょっと速度の調整は大丈夫そうです
The speed adjustment looks good.
これでいきます！
Let's do this!
凛として咲く花の如く
Like a Flower Blooming Proudly
譜面もいいですからね
The chart is great, too.
みんなの1番いい曲の1つですね
It's one of everyone's top favorite songs.
1番いい曲なんて何個あったっていいんですから
You can have as many "top favorite songs" as you want!
フレア、今日何回「1番いい曲の1つ」って言ってるでしょう
Flare's said "one of my top favorite songs" so many times today!
口癖みたいに言ってると思います
I think I'm saying it out of habit.
エルフレにもたくさん知ってもらいたいんですよね
I want the Elfriends to get to know lots of these songs too.
コナミさんの音ゲー曲にはたくさんいい曲があるということを
There are so many amazing songs in Konami's rhythm games.
ジャンジャン！ジャンジャンジャン！
Jan-jan! Jan-jan-jan!
SE歌いがち
I always end up singing the sound effects!
ここがね、この後か
This part... or is it right after?
こういうところ好きですよねー
Everyone loves parts like this, right?
咲いた
Bloomed~
咲いた咲いた
Bloomed, bloomed~
いい曲であり、譜面もいい
It's a great song, and the chart is good too.
ちょっとパカパカみたいな感じで
It's got that galloping feel to it.
ここ楽しいですよね
This part is so fun.
のー心ー！
~no kokoro!
ということで、ギリギリ！スコアが9万点いかないみたいな
And with that... barely! The score couldn't even reach 90,000 points...
これちょっと悔しいですね
That's a bit frustrating!
凛として咲く花の如く、ニューレコードだそうで
Looks like "Rin to shite Saku Hana no Gotoku" got a new record!
あ、これ自分のカード、マイカードなので
Ah, this is my own e-amusement card, so...
はい、ニューレコードだそうです。やっぱり配信バフなんですかね。ありがとうございました
Yep, a new record! Must be the stream buff. Thank you so much!
最後はですね、みんなでどうしても叫びたかったあの曲と言ったら、2択だと思うんですけど
For the last one... the song I really wanted to shout along with everyone... there are two choices, but...
ちょっとどうしてもみんなと叫びたい...
I really want to shout together with everyone...
ハンズアップに決まってるじゃないですか！
It's obviously "Hands Up"!
これ知らない方はね、カウントのあと、カウントあります。「3, 2... 4, 3, 2, 1」で「サンバ・デ・スクリーム」なんで、皆さんで叫びましょう！
For those who don't know, after the count... there's a count! After "4, 3, 2, 1", it's "Samba De Scream", so let me hear you all shout!
叫べるかな... ちょっと45だけど、これ45じゃないんじゃないかって言われてて、最後がすごい難しいんですよね
I wonder if I can shout... It's level 45, but people say it's harder than 45, and the end is super tough.
最後落としたらごめんなさい！
Sorry if I fail at the end!
これをみんなで叫ぶのが夢だったんですよね
It was my dream to shout this together with everyone.
GOLD RUSHとね どっちやろうかなって 迷いましたらば ちょっと Second Heavenにしました
I was torn between this and GOLD RUSH, but I ended up choosing Second Heaven.
なんかボーカル縛りと言いながら 2曲英語っていうｗ
Though I said I was doing vocal songs, having two English songs... (laughs)
あ、カウントダウン来ますよ！
Ah, the countdown is coming!
三倍アイスクリーム！
TRIPLE ICE CREAM!
みんなちゃんと言えました？
Did everyone manage to say it properly?
もう一回やりますからね
We'll do it one more time!
あ、正しい歌詞はぜひ調べてください
Ah, please look up the actual lyrics later!
生きがいなんだ！「3倍アイスクリーム」って言うことが生きがいなんだ！
It's my reason for living! Saying "Triple ice cream!" is my reason for living!
みんなこの配信を見たあと 明日はポップンやりに行きましょうね！
Everyone, after watching this stream, let's go play Pop'n tomorrow!
人の配信見てるとやりたくなりますからね
Watching someone else play makes you want to play it too!
ちょっと恥ずかしいんですけど 手元見られてるの
It's a bit embarrassing having my hand movements watched...
三倍アイスクリーム！
TRIPLE ICE CREAM!
急に叫ぶよ！
Suddenly shouting!
ちょっとここむずい！
Wait, this part is tough!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ああ、みんなで「3倍アイスクリーム」が言えて... 幸せだー！
Ah, being able to say "Triple ice cream" with everyone... I'm so happy!
いや本当にありがとうございました！
No, really, thank you so much!
あ、待って！でも3曲終わっちゃった！終わっちゃったよ！
Ah, wait! But all three songs are over! They're over!
あー楽しかったー！
Ah, that was so much fun!
もうなんか今日はね、3曲しか遊べないので... ここで終わってしまうんですけど... 実況プレイはここで終わっちゃうんですけど...
Since I can only play three songs today... it ends here, but... the gameplay portion ends here, but...
嫌だ嫌だ！離れたくない！もう...
No, no! I don't want to leave it! Aw...
うう... Flare今日はもうポップン... ずっとポップンと離れたくないよー！
Ugh... Flare doesn't want to be separated from Pop'n today... from Pop'n at all!
ポップンしたいよー！
I want to play Pop'n!
もう無いものはしょうがないか！ちょっと切り替えていきますか！
Well, can't be helped if there's no more! Let's switch gears!
まだですね、この後もみんなの好きな一番良い曲たくさん歌いますので、ちょっと楽しみにしてこの後も見てもらえたら嬉しいなって思います！
We still have more! After this, I'll be singing lots of everyone's favorite top songs, so I'd be really happy if you look forward to it and keep watching!
じゃあみんな、次に行くぞ！なんだ次の曲は！？
Alright everyone, onto the next one! What is the next song?!
回転頭から ない言語 ハイテンションと 固いテンポ i先導するジャイケン5から 大見解戦法
Rotating headless language, high tension and solid tempo, i leading jai ken 5 to the big interpretation tactics!
35＋4÷2すら はじけぬコンパ好き達に あっさり鈍角にねじ込む さばけた音楽鬼は
For party lovers who can't even solve 35+4÷2, the clever music demon easily screws it in at an obtuse angle!
どっからどこまでかわからん？が音分けた理由だ どいつとこいつのしゃべくりが 垂らした汗ふきな
"Don't know from where to where?" is why sound split up! Wipe off the sweat dripped from everyone's chatter!
デンダン変化つけた ×電波に乗る 大変馬鹿げた発言にゃグー おつむ事故り 人格すら 変わる程にあがる心拍数は
Adding den-dan variations, thumbs down to extremely silly radio statements! Mind crashing, heart rate rising so high it alters personality!
たっぷりあこぎだが、 におい棒を握る田と力 として生まれたときから 続けてきたこの遊び方
Pretty ruthless, but holding the magic wand with rice field and power, this way of playing since born as...
回転頭から ない言語 ハイテンションと 固いテンポ i先導するジャイケン5から 大見解戦法
Rotating headless language, high tension and solid tempo, i leading jai ken 5 to the big interpretation tactics!
３通り から４通り 本道理より 煩脳に まかせたきりを梱包し がっつり温厚に
3 ways to 4 ways, abandoning main logic for worldly desires, packing up everything left behind, staying completely gentle...
本当に この鈍行に跨がっていれば don't worry
Really, if you ride this local train, don't worry!
Don Pach Don Pach Don 今日で とことん交尾する日本島に
Don Pach Don Pach Don, on this Japanese island mating to the fullest today!
３通り から４通り 本道理より 煩脳に まかせたきりを梱包し がっつり温厚に
3 ways to 4 ways, abandoning main logic for worldly desires, packing up everything left behind, staying completely gentle...
本当に この鈍行に跨がっていれば don't worry
Really, if you ride this local train, don't worry!
Don Pach Don Pach Don 今日で とことん交尾する日本島に
Don Pach Don Pach Don, on this Japanese island mating to the fullest today!
Don Pach Don Pach Don 今日で
Don Pach Don Pach Don, today...
とことん交尾する日本鳥に
To the Japanese birds that mate to the extreme,
そんな時そんな調子 ぶち壊していくぜ日本調理だば
At times like that, with that vibe, we're gonna smash through! It's Japanese cooking!
お米の美味しい炊き方、そしてお米を食べることによるその効果。
[Song: How to Cook Delicious Rice, and the Effects of Eating Rice]
O! K-O-M-E!
O! K.O.! M.E.!
RICE! お米米 RICE!
RICE! Okome-kome RICE!
O! K.O.!
M.E.! OKOME!
RICE! お米米 RICE!
RICE! Okome-kome RICE!
SUPER FAR AWAY RELAXATION
1) 1合150cc 正確無比に計ること
1) Measure 1 gou (150cc) with utmost precision
2) 次に洗いだが直接米にお水をあてず二本指で
2) Next is washing: don't pour water directly on rice, use two fingers
3) お水を計り JOIN! するのだがその分量 米の1.2倍
3) Measure and JOIN! water: the amount should be 1.2 times the rice
その後は2時間ほどサディスティック(!?)にお水に浸して
After that, soak it sadistically (!?) in water for about 2 hours
ジャーの電源 ON!
Turn the rice cooker ON!
陽炎のような スチーム
Steam like a heat haze
底から かき混ぜて
Stir it up from the bottom!
お米 お米米
Rice, okome-kome
ビタミン ミネラル 食物繊維
Vitamins, minerals, dietary fiber
お米米 お米米
Okome-kome, okome-kome
Ah 食べて どすこい どすこい
Ah, eat it up! Dosukoi, dosukoi!
お米 お米米
Rice, okome-kome
おすもうさんの Power を GET!
GET the power of a sumo wrestler!
お米米 お米米
Okome-kome, okome-kome
あぁ 抱いてロマンティックに NIGHT FLIGHT
Ah, hold me for a romantic NIGHT FLIGHT
お米 お米米
Rice, okome-kome
4) 米屋のあの子をたぶらかそう!
4) Let's seduce that girl at the rice shop!
炊き放題 食べ放題
All-you-can-cook, all-you-can-eat
SO I LOVE YOU GET DAZE~!
お米 お米米
Rice, okome-kome
SUPER ENERGY MIRACLE POWER
お米米 お米米
Okome-kome, okome-kome
あぁん お米
Ahn, okome
5) お米おいしい
5) Rice is delicious
Homesick Pt.2&3
[Song: Homesick Pt.2&3]
真昼と真夜中の間に立つ歌は
The song standing between midday and midnight
真っ白なゲームといって耳もとではしゃぐ
Calls it a pure white game, frolicking by my ear
パーフェクト 僕らは完璧…なんて軽い冗談だった
Perfect, "we are perfect"... was just a light joke
いつも答えは 127の項目
The answer is always the 127th item
アスファルト蹴りあげたら
Once you kick up the asphalt
トランプで決めて
Decide with playing cards
急ぎ足で駆け出すのさ
And dash off with hurried steps
今すぐバスで
Right now by bus
そしてホームシック 抱えながら
And while carrying this homesickness,
人々は目指す
people head forward.
行き先はスマートに決めて
Decide your destination smartly,
願いを叶えたいのなら
if you want to fulfill your wish.
真夏と真冬の間に生まれた歌は
The song born between midsummer and midwinter
まったりなカーブ描いてどこまでも進む
Traces a gentle curve and moves onward endlessly
パーフェクト 全ては同じ 似たもの同士だった
Perfect, everything is the same, we were two of a kind
いつも答えは 同じ音なんだ
The answer is always the same sound
ソフトロックで暴れたら
If we go wild with soft rock,
トークバックで yeah!
with the talkback, yeah!
差し出したルール
The rules handed out,
12月のスポーツ
December sports,
バジルパスタの試食
tasting basil pasta.
明日の噂話を トランクに詰めて
Packing tomorrow's rumors into a trunk,
逆回しでやり直すのさ
we'll start over in reverse.
悪い性格
Bad personality,
それでホームシック語りながら
and while talking about homesickness,
人々は祈る
people pray.
行き先は満ちあふれてる
Destinations are overflowing,
誰かが待ちわびるから
because someone is eagerly waiting.
オレンジノイズ 浴びながら
Basking in the orange noise,
ショートカットで
taking a shortcut.
yeah!
新しいブーム 聞き飽きたフレーズ
A new trend, phrases I'm sick of hearing.
バブルアワーの法則
The rule of Bubble Hour.
さあ 明日の噂を トラックに乗せて
Come, put tomorrow's rumors on the track.
風に乗せて 薔薇撒くのさ
Riding the wind, scattering roses.
誰の計画？
Whose plan is this?
そしてホームシック 笑いながら 人々は迷う
And homesick, laughing as people wander.
行き先はそれぞれさ 皆
Everyone's destination is different,
旅の途中なんだから
because we're all in the middle of a journey.
風に乗って羽ばたくのは
Flapping wings while riding the wind,
カラスの計画
it's the crow's plan.
行き先はスピード上げて
Speeding up toward the destination,
この先もまだ続くなら
if it still continues beyond here...
続くなら
If it continues...
はい！ということで！聴いていただきました曲は、
Alright! The song you just listened to...
ジャンル名で言えばいいですか？ヒップロック、オコメメタル、ソフトロックということで、
Should I name the genres? It was Hip Rock, Ocome Metal, and Soft Rock!
ポルカと1曲、バカタレサーカスで2曲ということで、
One song with Polka and two songs with Bakatare Circus!
なんかオコメメタルとかでもバカタレサーカスでどうしてもやりたかったんですよね。
I really wanted to do Ocome Metal with Bakatare Circus no matter what.
増しても歌のうまいメンバーなんでね、皆集まってソフトロックとかで暴れ散らかしたりしたいなって思ったり、
They're all such amazing singers, so I wanted everyone to get together and go wild with Soft Rock and stuff.
ポルカはね、デスロウ好きということで、デスロウさんの曲を一緒に歌いたいなと思ったんでこのメンバーで選曲させていただきました！
And Polka loves Death Row, so I wanted to sing a Death Row song with her, which is why I chose these songs with this team!
ゲストはね、まだまだ居るのでお楽しみにということなんですけど、
We still have plenty of guests coming, so please look forward to it!
ちょっと早いんですけど、先にですね、今回ちょっとグッズの紹介をさせていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
It's a bit early, but may I go ahead and introduce this event's merch first?
また後でね、グッズの紹介は改めてさせていただきます。では行きます！
I'll introduce the merch again later as well. Here we go!
不知火フレア生誕記念2026！
Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration 2026!
早速、1つずつ見ていきましょう！
Let's check them out one by one!
まずは1つ目、マフラータオル！イラストはファルまろさんに描いていただきました！
First up is the Muffler Towel! The illustration was drawn by Farumaro-san!
とっても可愛い！持ち運びしやすいサイズ感なので、ぜひたくさん使ってください！
It's super cute! It's a convenient size to carry around, so please use it a lot!
2つ目はこちら、タンブラー！イラストは形状さんに描いていただきました！
Second is this Tumbler! The illustration was drawn by Keijo-san!
今回なんと、KONAMIさんに特別許諾をいただいて、推しのデザインに寄せさせていただきました！ありがとうございます！
This time, thanks to special permission from KONAMI, we were able to base the design on my fave! Thank you so much!
むらくもMZDのオマージュイラストなんですけど、のんびり寝ころぶフレアの横には、愛猫のノワチョコちゃんと、エルフレも一緒のとっても可愛いイラストとなってます！可愛すぎー！
It's an homage illustration to Murakumo MZD! Next to Flare lounging, there's my beloved cats Nowa and Choco, and Elflares together in this super cute illustration! Too cute!
大容量で1Lくらい入って、持ち手も付いてて飲みやすいので、ぜひみんなにも使ってほしいです！
It has a large capacity of around 1 liter and comes with a handle, making it easy to drink from, so I'd love for everyone to use it!
3つ目はこちら、ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー！お出かけ衣装のぬいぐるみが付いたスマホショルダーです！
Third is this Smartphone Shoulder Bag with Plushie! It's a smartphone shoulder bag featuring a plushie of my outing outfit!
ケースではないので、様々な機種のスマホが入るんですけど、全機種対応ではないので、サイズが合わなかった人はスマホ以外の小物を入れてください。ぜひいろんな場所に連れて行ってね！
It's not a phone case, so it fits various models, but it's not all-inclusive, so if your phone doesn't fit, please use it for other small items. Take it with you everywhere!
4つ目はこちら、キャップ！イラストの私とお揃いのキャップです！
Fourth is this Cap! It's a matching cap with the one I wear in the illustration!
今回のコンセプトで、帽子はどうしても外せなかったので、前出したものとは色とデザインを変えてみました！どうかな？可愛いかな？かっこいいかな？
With this concept, a hat was an absolute must, so I changed the color and design from the previous one! How is it? Cute? Cool?
シンプルめなデザインなので季節問わず被れるキャップです。みんなもお揃いにしてくれたら嬉しいな！
It has a simpler design, so you can wear it in any season. I'd be happy if everyone got matching ones!
5つ目はこちら、シチュエーションボイス！フレアと一緒に公園デート！
Fifth is this Situation Voice! A park date with Flare!
今回のグッズのイラストにあったような雰囲気のシチュエーションボイスになってます！みんな良かったら聴いてね！
The situation voice matches the vibe of the merch illustration! Please give it a listen if you'd like!
最後にフルセット！数量限定は直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード！通常版は箔押し複製メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードが付いてきます！
Finally, the Full Set! The limited edition includes an autographed Instax-style bromide card! The standard edition comes with a foil-stamped duplicate message Instax-style bromide card!
ふぅ〜、駆け足だったけど、どれもすごく可愛くて使いやすいと思うので、ぜひみんな買ってもらえると嬉しいです！
Phew, that was quick, but everything is super cute and practical, so I'd be really happy if you got them!
え〜、じゃあ、次の曲に行こうかな？
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
ゲストはちょっとまだいるので、嬉しい告知とかも残ってる...残ってる。
We still have more guests coming, and there are still exciting announcements left... left.
映ってるかな？
Is it on camera?
みんな、まだ帰らないでね！
Everyone, don't go home yet!
このあとも楽しんでね！
Please enjoy what's coming up next too!
追いかけても 追いかけても
Even if I chase, even if I chase,
するり指をぬける水のように
like water slipping through my fingers,
あなただけに あなただけに
only to you, only to you,
見つめられて漂う
stared at, I drift away.
流星の陰で 夢でも 捕まえて
In the shadow of a shooting star, catch me even in a dream.
流れる雲に思う
Watching the flowing clouds, I think
行き先ないこの心
of this heart with nowhere to go.
いつか見た日の明日も
Even tomorrow, like the days I once saw,
蒼い通り雨
is a blue passing shower.
色付いた花びら揺らす
Swaying colored petals,
ぬくもりも激しささえも
both the warmth and even the intensity,
刹那の裏側だけを残していく
leave behind only the other side of a moment.
かなうのなら かなうのなら
If it comes true, if it comes true,
駆け出して行きたい 風の中
I want to run out into the wind.
あなただけを あなただけを
Only you, if I gaze only at you,
見つめたなら 羽ばたく蝶のように
like a butterfly taking flight,
夢なら 見せないで
if it's a dream, don't show it to me.
星のない夜に 密かに
Secretly, on a starless night,
巡る季節を忘れて
forgetting the passing seasons,
いつか来る日の朝を
the morning of the day that will come
隠す 涙色
is hidden in the color of tears.
絡む指 湿めく吐息
Intertwined fingers, damp breath,
見つめ堕ち行く心
a heart gazing and falling down,
ひとときの ぬくもりさえも
even a moment's warmth,
忘れられずにまた一人 孤独
unable to forget, alone again in solitude.
追いかけたら 追いかけたら
If I chase, if I chase,
ふわり消えてしまう 月の影
it softly fades away, the shadow of the moon.
わたしだけに わたしだけに
Only to me, if you touch only me,
触れられたら 煌めく星のように
like a twinkling star,
嘘なら 抱きしめて
if it's a lie, hold me tight.
届くのなら 届くのなら
If it reaches, if it reaches,
明日さえ要らない 戻らない
I don't even need tomorrow, I won't go back.
離れてても 離れてても
Even if we are apart, even if we are apart,
心焦がす炎は あなただけ
the flame scorching my heart is only for you.
追いかけても 追いかけても
Even if I chase, even if I chase,
するり指をぬける水のように
like water slipping through my fingers,
わたしだけが わたしだけが
only I, only I,
時を止めた闇から手を伸ばす
reach out from the darkness where time has stopped.
かなうのなら かなうのなら
If it comes true, if it comes true,
駆け出して行きたい 風の中
I want to run out into the wind.
あなただけに あなただけに
Only to you, only to you,
心巡らすはるか 朧月
my heart turns toward the distant hazy moon.
嘘でも 抱きしめて
Even if it's a lie, hold me tight.
夢なら 醒めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake me up.
世界が輝くその瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとでも触れたくって
I want to touch it, even just a little.
ご覧よ幻を覗いて
Look, if you peek through the illusion,
空間が重なって溶けあう
space overlaps and melts together.
太陽と月のように
Like the sun and the moon,
時間を超えてはつながる
crossing time, it connects.
大胆不敵な空想の輪郭を追いかけて
Chasing the outline of a bold fantasy,
広がっては飲み込んでいく
it spreads and swallows it up.
世界が輝くその瞬間
The moment the world shines,
ちょっとでも触れたくって
I want to touch it, even just a little.
ご覧よ幻を覗いて
Look, if you peek through the illusion,
空間を飛び越した
space was transcended.
未来を追い越すその瞬間
The moment we pass the future,
いつでもこんなものなのさ
it's always like this.
幻を覗いた僕らの
Our world that peeked through the illusion
世界が溶けあう
melts together.
始まりと終わりのように
Like the beginning and the end,
混ざり合う音の感情
the emotions of blending sounds,
記憶を辿ればつながる
tracing memories will bring us together.
混ざり合うの
Blending together.
変幻自在に組まれた想像のパズルは
The puzzle of imagination, assembled in ever-changing shapes,
狂おしいほど美しいのだろう
must be maddeningly beautiful.
世界を飛び立つその瞬間
The instant you take off into the world,
どうしても見せたくて ごらんよ
I desperately wanted to show you, look,
見慣れない風景に そうさ今 駆け出した
into this unfamiliar scenery, yes, I've just started running.
未来が不安だった昨日は ちっぽけな何気ない今日なのさ
Yesterday, when I was anxious about the future, is now just a tiny, ordinary today.
幻のボクらの世界が重なる
Our illusory worlds overlap.
本当はずっと世界はボクを待ってた
The truth is, the world was waiting for me all along.
本当はずっとボクもキミを待っていたんだ
The truth is, I was waiting for you all along too.
重なり合った声が遠く響いて届く
Our overlapping voices echo far away and reach you.
聞こえるでしょう
You can hear it, right?
目をあけて物語が始まる時さ
Open your eyes, it's time for the story to begin.
世界が輝くその瞬間 ちょっとでも触れたくて ごらんよ
The moment the world shines, wanting to touch it even just a little, look,
幻のぞいて 空間を飛び越した
peeking into the illusion, leaping across space.
未来を追い越すその瞬間 いつでもこんなものなのさ
The moment we overtake the future, it's always like this.
幻をのぞいたボクらの世界が溶け合う
Peeking into the illusion, our worlds melt together.
はい！ということで聞いていただきました
Alright! You've just listened to
『Oboro』と『Harmonia』 2曲どうでしたか？
"Oboro" and "Harmonia." How did you like the two songs?
『Oboro』は俺の親友アイリスと2人で
For "Oboro," together with my best friend IRyS,
なんとダンエボのダンスを踊らせていただきました！
we actually got to perform the dance from DanceEvolution!
めっちゃ難しかった！
It was super tough!
どちらもね 大好きな曲なので
They're both songs that I absolutely love,
今回歌えてすごく嬉しかったです
so I'm really happy I got to sing them this time.
ここまでもですね 盛りだくさんだったんですけど
Up until now, it's already been packed with content,
ちょっとまだですね 嬉しいことがありまして
but there's actually another exciting thing!
なんとですね 今回ビッグな方をお呼びさせていただきまして
Believe it or not, I've invited a very special big guest today...
BEMANIシリーズで作曲をしてくださっている方を お呼びしたんですけど
someone who composes songs for the BEMANI series!
誰かな？誰かな？ちょっと待ってくださいね
Who could it be? Who is it? Please wait a moment.
誰かな？誰が...
Who is it? Who...
えっ？いいんですかね？これ...
Huh? Is this okay? This...
いいですか？えっ あの...
Is it alright? Um, well...
私がいちばん好きな曲と言っていました
The person who made what I called my favorite song...
音を作っております wacさんです！
who creates music, it's wac-san!
くるり！
Spin!
どうもー！よろしくお願いします！
Hello! Pleasure to be here!
よろしくお願いします！今日はありがとうございます！
Nice to meet you! Thank you so much for coming today!
いえいえ ありがとうございます
Not at all, thank you.
2Dで来たんですね！なんか舌伸びませんでした？
You came in 2D! Wait, didn't your tongue just stretch?
舌はね 伸びるんですよ にょーっと
My tongue stretches, you see. Boing!
あっ そう！結構長い！
Oh, really! It's pretty long!
今日はね これが精一杯なんですよ
Well, today, this is the best I can do.
今日はこれで許してほしいとのことなんですけど
He asks us to forgive him with this today, but...
自己紹介をしていただいても宜しいでしょうか？
Could you please introduce yourself?
わかりました 東京都江東区...
Sure. Koto Ward, Tokyo...
あっ 言っちゃっていいんですか？
Ah, wait, is it okay to say that?
コナミアケードゲームスよりやってまいりました 新人VTuberのwacです
Coming to you from Konami Arcade Games, I'm the rookie VTuber, wac!
よろしくお願いします！
Welcome!
困惑... 誰？って感じなんですかね？
Confusion... Are people like "Who's that?" or "What's going on?"
最近よくライブリとかでもやらせていただいているので
Lately I've been playing rhythm games on stream quite often,
結構うちのリスナーとかも知っているとか
so a lot of my viewers know about you,
元々音ゲーマーさんとかも知ってくださってると思うので
and rhythm gamers watching probably already know wac-san as well!
「これもwacさんなんだ」みたいに後から知る...
People often realize later on, "Oh, wac-san made this too!"
そうですね 知れば知るほど色々出てくるので
Right, the more you look into it, the more songs pop up.
一旦遊ばせていただいた 新筐体の話とか...
Let's talk a bit about that new arcade cabinet I got to play on...
あ、ぜひ！
Ah, please do!
12月18とかでしたっけ？
Was it around December 18th?
12月18日より順次稼働させていただいております
It's been rolling out sequentially starting December 18th.
ピカピカポップくんモデル 先ほど遊ばせていただいたんですけど
The shiny Pop-kun model that I got to try out earlier...
見た目がすごく可愛いですね！
it looks super cute!
ですよねー 超可愛いですよね
Right? It really is super cute.
個人的に液晶がめちゃめちゃ明るくて
Personally, I found the screen super bright
すごい見やすいです！ でっかいですしね
and really easy to see! / And it's huge, too.
そうなんですよ！大きければ大きいほどいいですからね！
Exactly! The bigger, the better, right?
大きければ大きいほどいいです
The bigger, the better indeed.
あと昔のキャラクターもすごく綺麗に映ったり...
Also, even older characters are displayed so crisp and clear...
そうですね
Indeed.
皆さんもう本当にね 今回ピカピカポップンミュージックモデルが
Everyone, truly, until this shiny new pop'n music model...
完成するまでには もうポップンスタッフの皆さんもそうですけども
...was completed, not only the Pop'n staff...
デスロウ先生や
...DES-ROW Sensei,
DJ YOSHITAKAさんや
DJ YOSHITAKA-san,
PONさんや
PON-san,
猫叉Masterさんや
Nekomata Master-san,
TAGさんや
TAG-san,
あさきさんや
Asaki-san,
劇団レコードさん
Gekidan Record-san,
K-Gくん
K-G-kun,
タニチュウくん
Tanichu-kun...
もういっぱいです
...so many people were involved!
筐体を作っていただいた方々も、運んでくれた方々もいらっしゃいますし
There are people who built the cabinets, and those who transported them.
感謝の気持ちで私生きております
I live every day with a heart full of gratitude.
この場に立てたのも皆さんの所為でございます
Being able to stand here today is all thanks to everyone.
いや、それは本当にもう、こちらが「ありがとうございます」なんですけれども
No, really, we are the ones who should be thanking you!
ここまで辿り着けたのも、色々な方々のご尽力あってのことでございますので
Reaching this point was only possible thanks to everyone's hard work.
ということなんですけれども、ポップンミュージックの初出し情報とかあります？
Speaking of which, do you have any brand-new Pop'n Music info to reveal?
それはちょっと... / あ、言えない？ / いや、言います
Mascot: "Well..." Flare: "Can't say?" Mascot: "No, I'll spill!"
初出し情報って何が良いですか？
What kind of exclusive info would you like?
私個人としてはMZDの話とか聞きたいんですけど...
Personally, I'd love to hear some lore about MZD...
MZD？神ですね？
MZD? You mean God, right?
神だからあの神ですね？
Since he's God, he's that God, right?
結構wacさんってMZDの半分くらいだと思ってて...
I felt like wac-san makes up about half of MZD...
半分？！ / 半分はPONさんなんですよ
Mascot: "Half?!" Flare: "And the other half is PON-san!"
厳密に言うと「M」くらいですね
Strictly speaking, he's just the "M" part.
「Z」がPONさんで、「D」がその他みんなみたいな...
"Z" is PON-san, and "D" is everyone else...
くらいの配分ですね / あーなるほどなるほど
Mascot: "...is about the ratio." Flare: "Ah, I see, I see!"
なのでMZDの話、話せる範囲で聞けたら嬉しいなーって
So if there's anything about MZD you can share, I'd love to hear it!
MZDの何を知りたいんだい？
What is it you want to know about MZD?
キャラ設定とか...
Like character settings/lore...
なんかアマゾン側... / 領域、青基調ですか？ / 青基調ですね
Mascot: "Like the Amazon side..." Flare: "Is his realm blue-themed?" Mascot: "It is blue."
なんでか知らんのです / なん知らんのかい！
Mascot: "I don't know why though." Flare: "You don't know?!"
でも昔アマゾンみたいな槍持ってましたよね？ / 鍵ですね
Mascot: "But he used to carry an Amazon-like spear, right?" Flare: "That was a key."
あれがアマゾンなのかもしれない
Maybe that key was the Amazon element.
アマゾン要素そこなんですね / うん、多分
Flare: "So that was the Amazon element?!" Mascot: "Yeah, probably."
今も青基調に住んでるんですかね？ / 多分...
Flare: "Is he still living in the blue realm?" Mascot: "Probably..."
これなんかあれですね
This feels like...
公式さんと話す話...
...a conversation meant for the official developers!
ポップンは本当、公式が知らないこといっぱいあるんですよ
Actually, in Pop'n, there's a lot even the official team doesn't know!
皆さんの色んな思いで出来てるので、公式こそ知らないこともいっぱいあるんで
It's made from everyone's feelings, so there are many things even official staff don't know.
あとからついたりとかする事もあるんですかね？
Do settings get added later on as well?
曲作ってからキャラクター決まるんですか？それともキャラに合わせて曲作るんですか？
Do you make songs before picking characters, or write songs to fit existing characters?
結構ケースバイケースというか...
It's pretty much case-by-case...
特にMZDとかは決まってることが多いですよね、やっぱり
But especially with MZD, things are usually predetermined.
割とバージョンの最後の曲だったりすることが多いんで
He often gets assigned to the final song of a version...
MZDありきで曲を作んなきゃいけないことは多いです
...so we frequently have to compose songs with MZD specifically in mind.
特にこのキャラ好きな人が「このキャラに曲付けたい」って場合もあります
Also, sometimes a creator who loves a character asks to write a song for them.
あー、なるほどー！
Ah, I see!
「Jam&Fizz」にもMZDが出てくるとフレアは期待しているんですけど...
Flare is hoping MZD will appear in "Jam&Fizz" too...
出てくるといいなー
I hope he shows up!
うさ猫の時みたいにストーリーしっかりみたいなのって今後もあったりするんですか？
Will there be solid story elements in the future, like during the UsaNeko era?
ストーリー、どうなんですかね？
Story, huh? I wonder...
ポップンお好きな方って、そういうストーリー的な...
Do Pop'n fans enjoy story elements where...
「このキャラこんなんだったんだ」みたいなのが分かると嬉しいのかな？
...they get to discover "Ah, so that's what this character was like"?
めっちゃ嬉しいです！本で出してほしいまである！
It makes us extremely happy! I even want it published as a book!
推しの情報を常に募集しているので、お願いします！
I'm always looking for info on my favorite characters, so please!
マジですか？頼まれちゃいました
Really? You're asking me for real?
何卒お願い... / 大先輩のお願いとあってはね...
Flare: "Please, I beg you..." Mascot: "When a grand senior asks..."
星にお願い！ / 欲張りなのって大事ですよ
Flare: "A wish upon a star!" Mascot: "Being ambitious is important, yes!"
私今日、実は誕生日なんですけど... / え、マジですか？
Flare: "Actually, today is my birthday..." Mascot: "Wait, really?!"
おめでとう！歌いましょうか / え、歌ってくれるんですか？
Mascot: "Happy Birthday! Shall I sing?" Flare: "Eh, you'll sing for me?"
おめでとー お誕生日ー / これ今日実装されますか？って
Mascot: "Happy birthday to you~" Flare: "Is this getting implemented today?!"
ありますか？
I wonder if it will?
誕生日なんで、もしよろしければサインとかいただき... / サイン？
Flare: "Since it's my birthday, if possible, a signature..." Mascot: "An autograph?"
嬉しいなーって / そんなん何歩でもしましょう、借用書じゃなければ！
Flare: "That'd make me so happy..." Mascot: "I'll sign as many as you want, as long as it's not an IOU!"
全然書きます書きます！
I'll gladly sign them!
今日２枚サイン用意したんですけど... / あ、カードですね！びっくりしたー
Flare: "I prepared two cards for signing..." Mascot: "Ah, cards! You scared me!"
やっぱり音ゲーマーといえばカードなんだ！
When you think rhythm gamers, you think cards!
e-amusement passを2枚用意しました。普通のやつと「しごとねこ」のカードを。ネコなだけに！
I prepared two e-amusement passes: a regular one and a "Shigoto Neko" one, since you're a cat!
なるほど、ネコだけに！どちらにサインしてもらえても嬉しい！
Mascot: "I see, cat-themed!" Flare: "I'd be happy with a signature on either!"
ここらへんに後で出していただけるかなと思うので
They'll probably display them right around here later on.
大丈夫です、書きます書きます！ / よろしくお願い...ありがとうございます！
Mascot: "No problem, I'll sign them!" Flare: "Thank you so much!"
埋め尽くします！すべてを消し去る勢いで埋め尽くします！
I'll fill the whole card! I'll cover it so completely it erases everything!
あわよくば、私BEMANlの楽曲が大好きなので...
If possible... I really love BEMANI songs, so...
いつかカバーとか入ったら嬉しいなーとか...
...if I could do a cover someday, I'd be so happy...
おや？おや？ / あ、ちょっと欲張りすぎました
Mascot: "Oh? Oh?" Flare: "Ah, I got a bit too greedy!"
これもしや... / 流石に欲張りすぎました、ごめんなさい！
Mascot: "Could this be..." Flare: "I was definitely too greedy, sorry!"
いや、フレアさん！お待たせしました、案件です！ / ありがとうございます！
Mascot: "No, Flare-san, the wait is over! It's a sponsored gig!" Flare: "Thank you!"
ここまで溜めに溜めて案件です！ / 案件なんですね！
Mascot: "Building up all this anticipation for a deal!" Flare: "So it's a real sponsorship!"
「案件なんだな」って思ってる君たち、本当に無かったんだからね！
To all of you thinking "This was sponsored all along", we really didn't have one until now!
ありませんでした。
There wasn't one.
なんですけど、あの、今回あの、
However, this time...
なんと、今wacさんが言ってくださった通り、
As wac-san just mentioned...
ちょっと不知火フレア、BEMANIにコラボ決定しました！
a Shiranui Flare x BEMANI collaboration has been decided!
決定しました！ ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
やったー！
Hooray!
やりましたね！ ありがとうございます！
We did it! Thank you so much!
めちゃめちゃ嬉しいです！ ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
なんか、えーと、どこを触れていいのかなと…
I wonder what part I should talk about first...
どのゲームとしましょうか、っていう話で…
Regarding which game we should collaborate with...
え、ポップン、ポップン、ポップン…
Um, Pop'n, Pop'n, Pop'n...
まあそうですね。ポップンさすがにこれ無かったらわけが分からないんですけども…
Well, yeah. If Pop'n wasn't included, it wouldn't make any sense...
ここまででして… / そうですよね。
Up until now... / Right.
もちろんポップンもですし、さらに今回…
Of course Pop'n Music, and on top of that, this time...
SOUND VOLTEXとDanceDanceRevolutionと3機種でのコラボをさせていただきたいと思っております。
we're collaborating across three titles, including SOUND VOLTEX and DanceDanceRevolution!
えー！ すごーい！
Wow! Amazing!
これは、あの、私の曲が移植される…
Does this mean my songs will be ported?
それはもちろん…
That, of course...
もちろん曲ですよ。
Of course, songs!
新曲いきましょうよ。
Let's go with a new song!
新曲！？
A new song?!
新曲。実はね、ちょっとね、この人がいいんじゃないかなーと思ってるんですよね。
A new song. Actually, I was thinking this person might be great...
曲作ってもらうなら。
to compose the song for us.
誰なんだろう…
I wonder who...
はい、先ほど、MとかZとかDとか言ってたんで…
Yes, earlier you were mentioning M, Z, or D...
今回はその、Zにお願いしようかなーと思ってます。
So this time, I was thinking of asking Z!
Zって誰だっけ？
Who was Z again?
えーと、Z… Z誰だったっけ？
Um, Z... who was Z again?
ポですね、ポ。 ポ、ポです。
It's P, P.
ポンです。P-O-N、ポンというね…
It's PON. P-O-N, PON!
あ、兄ちゃんさん！ / なかなかいい曲を書く子がいるんですよ。
Ah, Niichan-san! / There's someone who writes really great songs.
へぇー！ / ポップンミュージック… 先ほど、そうですね…
Oh! / Pop'n Music... earlier, that's right...
まあフレアさんはm&dの曲が好きっておっしゃってましたけど、まあ1/3くらい作って… 最近結構m&dの曲いっぱいまた作ってます。
Flare-san said she likes m&d's songs, which they made about a third of... lately they've been making a lot of m&d songs again.
し、まあそれ本人も歌うし、あの、女性ボーカリストの曲もいっぱい書いてるような…
And he sings himself, plus he writes a lot of songs for female vocalists...
P-O-N、ポンさんが…
P-O-N, PON-san...
wacさんとポンさんが、あの、一番好きなんですよね！
Actually, wac-san and PON-san are my absolute favorites!
マジすか？ ありがとうございます！
Really? Thank you so much!
ううっ… ちょっと涙が出ちゃう…
Ugh... I'm getting a little teary-eyed...
あ、隠れ… 出てきてください！ / ありがとうございます！ 楽しみ！
Ah, hidden... Please come back out! / Thank you so much! I'm excited!
待ってます。
I'm looking forward to it.
せっかくなんだんですけど、来て、wacさん来ていただいたから…
Since wac-san is here today...
なんか良かったら、実機に収録される楽曲を…
If it's okay, I'd love to perform...
wacさんと一緒に、なんか、やりたいなと思うんですけど…
together with wac-san right now.
歌えます？ / いいでしょう！
Can you sing? / Sure, why not!
せっかくなので、あの、2人だけでやりましょう。
Since we're here, let's do it with just the two of us.
ピアノと歌だけで。
Just piano and vocals.
えー！？
Huh?!
イイんじゃないですか？
Isn't that great?
え、めっちゃ嬉しい！ 緊張します！
I'm so happy! I'm getting nervous!
めちゃくちゃ緊張してますけど自分も。
I'm extremely nervous myself!
頑張ります！ 頑張ります！
I'll do my best! I'll do my best!
頑張ります。実はね、練習してます。自分、このために。
I'll do my best. Actually, I've been practicing for this!
マジですか！ 楽しみ！
Really?! I'm excited!
はい、聞いていただきたい、ぜひ。
Yes, I'd really love for you to listen.
はい、では、フレア、wacさんによる… 聞いてください。
Okay then, performed by Flare and wac-san... Please listen to...
『僕の飛行機』
"My Airplane"
[僕の飛行機 - 作詞・作曲・編曲: 宮本ひろみ / Konami Arcade Games]
[My Airplane - Lyrics/Music: Miyamoto Hiromi / Konami Arcade Games]
どこまで飛べるかを
To see how far I can fly...
確かめに僕ら 旅に出る
To find out, we set off on a journey.
夢は尽きること 忘れて
Forgetting that dreams can end,
草原を駆け抜けて行ったけど
we ran through the grassy plains, but...
幼い憧れと
Our youthful yearning...
ほどけた指切り 絆にする
We turned broken pinky promises into our bond.
逃げ出せないから ただ空を見てた
Unable to run away, I just stared at the sky.
かっこ悪いから 嘘をついた
Because I was embarrassed, I told a lie.
白いノート 一枚破って
Tearing out a single page from a white notebook,
今日の日付と さようなら託した 紙飛行機
a paper airplane entrusted with today's date and a goodbye...
風に乗って 舞い上がって 蒼く溶けた
Riding the wind, soaring high, melting into the blue.
旅立ちの歌を背に 白い軌道追いかけて
With the song of departure at my back, chasing the white contrail,
ここで見てた 淡い夢も
the faint dreams I watched from here, too...
翼にして いつか誰かに届いてくれる？
Turning them into wings, will they reach someone someday?
僕の飛行機
My airplane...
乗り込んだ汽車が
The train I boarded...
見上げてた空へ
toward the sky I looked up at...
続くなら
if it continues there...
夢をみてた遠い日々に
To those distant days when I had dreams,
取り残されてる記憶は
the memories left behind
まだあの空を覚えてるから
still remember that sky.
絡み合ってもつれ合ってやがて一人
Entangled, intertwined, eventually alone,
さよならの歌胸に約束を数えてるけど
With a song of farewell in my heart, I count my promises,
ここで見てた淡い夢も翼にして
turning even the faint dreams I saw here into wings,
きっとどこまでも追い付けと信じてる
believing I can surely catch up no matter how far.
風に乗って舞い上がって蒼く溶けた
Riding the wind, soaring up, melting into the blue,
あの紙飛行機は誰の手にとどいたろうか
whose hands did that paper airplane reach?
夢が覚めて僕が空に還るときも
Even when the dream wakes and I return to the sky,
ずっと変わらずに僕は君の中に生きてる
unchangingly, I will live on inside you.
うわー！ アレンジすごい！ いや、ありがとうございました！
Aah! The arrangement was amazing! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
めちゃめちゃ貴重な... 経験をさせていただき...
I had such a precious experience...
こちらこそ。はい、ありがとうございました。
Likewise. Thank you very much.
はい！ ありがとうございます！ wacさんでした！
Yes! Thank you so much! That was wac-san!
はい、作曲担当のwacです。
Yes, wac, the composer.
一言最後にあります？
Do you have any final words?
いやいや、もう本当に、この度は素晴らしい機会をいただきまして、こちらこそありがとうございました。
No, no, really, thank you so much for giving me this wonderful opportunity.
はい、今後ともぜひpop'n music、BEMANIシリーズをよろしくお願いいたします。
Please continue to support pop'n music and the BEMANI series in the future.
よろしくお願いします！
Please do!
はぁ〜！ いや〜本当に嬉しいですね！ 大好きな『僕の飛行機』をwacさんと一緒にお届けしました！
Phew~! Ah, I'm really so happy! I delivered my beloved "Boku no Hikouki" together with wac-san!
アレンジバージョンどうでしたか？ めっちゃすごかったですよね！
How was the arranged version? It was super amazing, right?
wacさんからご提案いただきまして、今回アレンジバージョンで歌わせていただきました！ めちゃめちゃ嬉しい！
wac-san made the proposal, and I got to sing the arranged version this time! I'm super happy!
もう、なんか... 思い残すことがない... あ、まだ思い残すことはたくさんある！ ね！ だってコラボとかもありますからね！
I have no... regrets left... Ah, wait, I still have plenty of things left to do! Right! Because there are still collabs and things coming up!
あ、でですね、あの... ここで新曲が出ます！
Ah, and also... a new song is coming out here!
なんかヌルッと出てきたんですけど、これさっき言ってた、あの、wacさんが言ってたのじゃなくて、私個人のあの新曲が出ます！
It kind of slid in smoothly, but this isn't what wac-san was talking about earlier, it's my personal new song!
『Silent Flame, Never Fade』という曲になります。
It's titled "Silent Flame, Never Fade".
で、作詞作曲がですね、fripSideさんの八木沼悟志さんに、あの、作っていただきました！
And as for the songwriting and composition, Satoshi Yaginuma-san from fripSide created it for me!
配信のあとMVも出ますので、お楽しみに〜ということで、デジタルリリースはこのあと0時からとなっております！
The MV will also be released after the stream, so look forward to it! The digital release starts tonight at midnight!
そしてですね、なんと！ この新曲『Silent Flame, Never Fade』が... pop'n music、DanceDanceRevolution、SOUND VOLTEXの3機種に収録されます！ すげぇ〜！
And also, what a surprise! This new song "Silent Flame, Never Fade" will be included in pop'n music, DanceDanceRevolution, and SOUND VOLTEX! Amazing~!
マジか... なんか感想って言われてたけど、マジかしかちょっと出てこないんですけど...
Seriously...? When asked for my thoughts, all I can say is "Seriously?"...
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you so much!
このほかの詳細もですね、生誕グッズも含めて最後に改めてお知らせしますので、お待ちください！
Other details, including birthday merchandise, will be announced again at the end, so please stay tuned!
ではですね、早速今お知らせしました新曲をですね、聴きたいと思いますので、お披露目しようかなと思います！
So then, I'd like us to listen to the new song I just announced right away, so I'll be presenting it!
それでは聴いてください、『Silent Flame, Never Fade』！
Now then, please listen: "Silent Flame, Never Fade"!
静かに揺れ続ける焔 名もなき道照らし出す
Quietly, the flickering flame illuminates the nameless road.
失くしていた未来さえ 今あなたと新たな明日を刻んだ
Even the lost future, now with you, carves a new tomorrow.
いくつもの夜を越えて
Overcoming countless nights,
紡いできた 自分らしさ
The uniqueness I've woven together,
選択した その全てが
Everything I have chosen
私をまた 突き動かす
Drives me forward once again.
強がってた 訳じゃなくて
It wasn't that I was pretending to be strong,
止まることが 怖かったよ
I was just afraid of stopping.
迷っていた あの日もきっと
Even those days when I was lost,
今のチカラになってるよ
Have surely become my strength today.
一人きりだと思っても
Even if I think I'm all alone,
気づけば そこにある笑顔が
Before I know it, the smiles right there
私といつも 一緒に歩いてくれた
Have always walked alongside me.
その意味 そのチカラ 絶対に離さない！
That meaning, that strength, I will never let go!
加速していく この想いは
These feelings that keep accelerating
いま翼を 纏い出す
Are now wrapping themselves in wings.
私が私でいれる
Being able to stay as myself,
それだけで十分だから
That alone is more than enough,
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away
強くなったからじゃない
Is not because I became strong.
私を呼ぶ その声と
With that voice calling out to me,
重ね合った 信じる世界の明日を
We overlapped, believing in tomorrow's world.
傷つくこと ためらってた
I hesitated, afraid of getting hurt,
立ち止まったこともあった
And there were times I came to a standstill.
そんな時に この背中を
At times like that, the gaze
押してくれた その眼差し
That pushed me from behind...
迷いながら 選んだ道
The path I chose while lost,
間違いさえ 真実だと
Even my mistakes were a part of truth.
その炎は 闇を照らして
That flame illuminated the darkness
私に正しさをくれた
And gave me righteousness.
張り裂けそうに痛んでも
Even if it hurts to the point of breaking,
この胸に刻んだ勇気が
The courage engraved in my chest
私をいつも支えてくれていたから
Has always supported me,
今ここに感じ合う あなたと私の夢
So now we feel it together—your dream and mine.
燃え尽きることの無い夢は
A dream that will never burn out
この大空に羽ばたいて
Flaps its wings into this vast sky,
涙さえも輝かせ
Making even tears shine bright,
誰かの夜を照らしたい
I want to illuminate someone's night.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away
強くなったからじゃない
Is not because I became strong.
静かな焔を抱いて
Embracing a quiet flame,
何度だって立ち上がれること知ったから
Because I learned I can rise up again and again.
たとえ世界が色を失い
Even if the world loses its color
光が遠ざかっても
And the light fades far away,
この名に刻む焔は
The flame engraved in this name
あなたと私を繋いで
Binds you and me together.
逃げないって決めたのは
The reason I decided not to run away
強くなったからじゃない
Is not because I became strong.
私を呼ぶ その声と
With that voice calling out to me,
重ね合った 信じる世界の明日を
We overlapped, believing in tomorrow's world.
この後詳細お知らせ！まだ帰らないでね！
[Detailed announcement after this! Don't leave yet!]
不知火フレア生誕祭2026 BEMANI楽曲3D LIVE 見に来てくれて本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming to watch the Shiranui Flare Birthday Fest 2026 BEMANI Songs 3D LIVE!
今回のこのコラボは、本当に生誕ライブを企画する際に最初から決まっていたものではなく…
This collaboration wasn't something decided from the start when planning the birthday live...
みんなが声を上げて盛り上げてくれたから叶った案件なので…
It was a project that happened because you all voiced your support and brought the hype...
改めて皆さんにお礼を言わせてください。本当にありがとうございます！
So let me thank you all once again. Thank you so very much!
よーし、気になる不知火フレア BEMANIコラボ…
Alright! As for the exciting Shiranui Flare BEMANI collaboration...
案内よ！発表していくよ！
I'm making the announcement now!
改めて、今回コラボするゲームは...
Once again, the games we're collaborating with are...
pop'n music,
DanceDanceRevolution,
SOUND VOLTEXの3機種です！
and SOUND VOLTEX, three games in total!
この3機種に、先ほど披露した...
Into these three games, the song I just performed...
「Silent Flame, Never Fade」が収録されます！
"Silent Flame, Never Fade" will be included!
ご覧の日時から、プレイすることができますので、お楽しみに！
You can play it starting from the dates shown, so please look forward to it!
さらにさらに！不知火フレアが歌う...
Furthermore! Shiranui Flare's cover of...
BEMANIシリーズのカバー楽曲の収録も決定しました！
a song from the BEMANI series is also confirmed to be included!
収録楽曲、収録機種、収録日時についてはご覧のとおりです。
As for the included songs, games, and dates, please see the screen.
そして！まだまだ終わりません！
And! That's not all!
BEMANIアーティストとのコラボ新曲の制作が決定しましたー！
A new collaboration song with a BEMANI artist is being produced!
続報は、pop'n music公式Xで発信予定ですので、ぜひチェックしてみてください！
Further updates will be posted on the official pop'n music X account, so be sure to check it out!
さ、ここからは、各機種ごとのコラボ内容をまとめてご紹介していきます！
Now, let me introduce the collaboration details for each game!
pop'n musicでは、なんと不知火フレアがポップンキャラとして登場します！
In pop'n music, Shiranui Flare will appear as a Pop'n character!
さらに、ゲームをもっと楽しくプレイできるコラボカスタマイズアイテムも登場します！
Plus, collaboration customization items to make playing even more fun will also appear!
詳細は追って公式Xにて発表予定なので、お見逃しなく！
Details will be announced on the official X later, so don't miss out!
DanceDanceRevolutionでは、ゲーム画面の見た目を自分好みに変更できるプレミアムカスタマイザ―としてコラボアイテムが登場予定です！
In DanceDanceRevolution, collaboration items will appear as Premium Customizers to personalize your screen!
SOUND VOLTEXでは、これまでホロライブメンバーも登場してきたネメシスクルーに不知火フレアも新加入します！
In SOUND VOLTEX, Shiranui Flare will join as a Nemesis Crew member alongside previous Hololive members!
さらにカスタマイズアイテムとして登場予定です！
In addition, customization items will also appear!
こちらも詳細は追って公式Xにて発表していくので、忘れずにチェックしてね！
Details on this will also be announced on the official X later, so remember to check!
ということで！
And so...
今回はフレアがずっと愛してやまないBEMANIシリーズのオリジナルソング縛りのライブがしたい
This time, I really wanted to do a 3D live featuring only original songs from the BEMANI series I love so much,
というね、あのー完全にフレアのやりたい放題ライブの企画だったわけなんですが、
so it was a project born purely out of my own wishlist, but...
そこからこんなにたくさんゲームに実装されてしまうなんて、未だにちょっと現実味がありませんが、
To think it resulted in being implemented in so many games, it still feels surreal...
長らく愛しているBEMANIユーザーさんも末永く今後ともBEMANIシリーズのこと、よろしくお願いします！
To all long-time BEMANI players, please continue to support the BEMANI series for a long time to come!
あ、不知火フレアもよければよろしくお願いします！
Ah, and please support Shiranui Flare too if you'd like!
ということで、あの、音ゲーマー特有の「誰視点？」ですが...
So, that was my typical rhythm gamer "From whose perspective?" moment, but...
えー、すでに遊んでいるエルフレはもちろん、まだ始めていないエルフレもこれを機に遊んでもらえたら嬉しいです！
whether you're an Elfriend who already plays or someone who hasn't started yet, I'd be happy if you gave it a try!
そして新曲もね、このあとMVが公開されるのと、
Also for the new song, the MV will be released after this,
0時にはリリースもされるので、たくさん聴いて観てくれると嬉しいです！
and it will be released digitally at midnight, so I hope you'll listen to and watch it a lot!
あと、グッズ！
Also, merchandise!
えー、今回ですね、少し早めにお知らせさせていただいたので、さらっと振り返るね。
Since we announced them a bit early today, let's quickly review them.
マフラータオル、タンブラー、ぬいぐるみ付きスマホショルダー、キャップ、シチュエーションボイス、フルセット！
Muffler towel, tumbler, smartphone shoulder bag with plushie, cap, situation voice, and full set!
どれも可愛くて使いやすいと思うので、ぜひお仕事だったり、お出かけとか、えー、スポーツとか、えー、ゲームセンターとか行ったりとか、えー、なんでも使ってみてください！
They're all super cute and easy to use, so please use them at work, going out, sports, or heading to the arcade!
グッズの販売はこのあと21時半からなので、数量限定もたくさん用意しているので、焦らずにね！
Merchandise sales start at 21:30 right after this. There are plenty of limited items available, so don't rush!
裏話なんかは、また改めてお話しさせてください。
I'll share more behind-the-scenes stories another time.
今回は思いもよらないことが本当にたくさん起きて、運営さんもKONAMIさんもエルフレのみんなも感謝の気持ちでいっぱいです。本当にありがとうございます！
So many unexpected wonderful things happened, and I'm full of gratitude to management, KONAMI, and all Elfriends. Thank you so much!
さ、明日はゲームセンターに行っちゃう？行っちゃう？ね、一緒に行こ？
Now, shall we head to the arcade tomorrow? Shall we? Hey, let's go together!